Grant, John, Pipe-major. John Grant collection of bagpipe music, 1908-1947 (MS Mus 120-120.6): Guide.
John Grant collection of bagpipe music,
1908-1947.
Houghton Library, Harvard College Library, Harvard University
MS Mus 120
MS Mus 120.1
MS Mus 120.2
MS Mus 120.3
MS Mus 120.4
MS Mus 120.5
MS Mus 120.6
Grant, John, Pipe-major.
13 volumes and 3 boxes (4 linear ft.)
Manuscripts on the history of bagpipe music by Scottish musician and music historian John Grant.
65M-47. Purchased with the Robinson fund from Frank Hammond, 63, Birmingham Road, Sutton, Coldfiel Warwickshire, England; received: 1965 August 16.
There are no restrictions on physical access to this material. Collection is open for research.
Grant, a Scot, wrote histories of bagpipe music and compositions for the highland bagpipe.
Arranged alphabetically by title.
Contains bound volumes of Grant's original manuscripts for history of bagpipe music, with text, photographs, and colored illustrations. Also, manuscripts of his music for the highland bagpipe and instructions for playing the instrument.
- Grant, John. A choice collection of Piobaireachd or highland bagpipe music. A.MS.s.; Edinburgh, 1946., fMS Mus 120; 1v.
- Grant, John. The great highland bagpipe and its music. A.MS.s.; Edinburgh, 1930., fMS Mus 120.1; 4v.
  - vol. I
  - vol. II
  - vol. III
  - vol. IV
- Grant, John. The highland bagpipe instructor. A.MS.s.; Edinburgh, [n.d.]., fMS Mus 120.2; 2v.
- Grant, John. The music of the Mac Crimmons. A.MS.s.; Edinburgh, 1947., fMS Mus 120.3; 1v.
- Grant, John. The royal collection of Piobaireachd. A.MS.s.; Edinburgh, 1908-1923., fMS Mus 120.4; 4v.
  - "Lament for her Most Excellent Majesty Queen Victoria" p.1
- Grant, John. The royal collection of highland bagpipe music. A.MS.s.; Edinburgh, 1946., fMS Mus 120.5; 1v.
- Grant, John. [39 incidental compositions for the highland bagpipe] A.MS.s.; Edinburgh, [v.d.]., pfMS Mus 120.6; 3 boxes.